# 这次我们没有点很多
This time we didn't order much
# 就是两个大肉串
Just two big mutton kebabs
# 还有两个烤包子
and also two Kao Baozi (lit. baked bun stuffed with mutton)
# 烤包子呢 是5块
5 yuan for one Kao Baozi
# 这个肉串是10块
10 yuan for one kebab
# 啊 看着就想吃
Ah, I'm already hungry by just looking at it
# （附加文字：没错，我就是这么美味）
(y'right, I AM delicious)
# 因为这个包子是烤的嘛
Because this Baozi is baked
# 很烫
It is very hot
# 它的外面好像会有点脏
Its crust might look a little dirty
# 或者说 有烤的不好的地方
Or you can say those overcooked part
# 可以用锉刀 把它 就是刮一下
You can scrape it off with a scrapper
# 烤的不好的地方 刮一下
those overcooked parts
# 这个就是我们的锉刀
This is scrapper
# 把它刮一下
scrape a few times
# 太烫了
Too hot!
# 这个包子特别硬
This Baozi is very hard
# 我说把它能够当砖头
I dare say you can use it as a brick
# 真的是一点都不过分
which is definitely not an exaggeration
# 真的是一点都不过分 太硬了
No exaggerating, such a hard crust
# 我掰一下试试吧
Let me try to break
# 哇
wow
# 它这里面的羊肉肥瘦相间
The mutton inside is a mixture of the fat and the lean part
# 而且你能看到明显的肥肉
You can easily see the fat
# 它这个皮特别厚
It has a very thick crust
# 即使里面有很多的汤汁
Even if there is lots of gravy in it
# 都不会漏出来
it would not leak out
# 这个10块钱的烤串
This 10-yuan kebab
# 差不多吧 8块肉
I think it's worth the price, about 8 lumps of meat
# 真是 羊肉大块吃起来才爽
Truly, it is so satisfying to eat big lumps of mutton
# 它这个羊肉吃起来特别嫩
The mutton is very tender
# 外面可能是因为有面糊
Probably because of the flour paste outside
# 烤出来带这种脆脆的口感
It is roasted to crispy
# 真的是
really
# 吃起来特别爽
It tastes so cool
# 如果是普通人来吃饭
One Kao Baozi should be enough
# 一般一个烤包子就差不多了
for an ordinary meal to a regular person
# 饭量大一点（的人）
Those who have a big appetite
# 可以再要一个肉串 就差不多了
can have an extra kebab, which will also be enough
# 再多 真的就吃不了了
You cannot eat more than these
# 刚才 我弄包子砸自己脑袋的时候
(said after the uncle left) There was an old uncle laughing at me
# 旁边吃包子的大爷都笑了
when I hit my head with the Kao Baozi
# 他可能心想
He might be thinking that
# 这怕是个傻子
"I'm afraid she's a fool!"
# 在这边你很少看到 像（苍蝇 蚊子）
Here you barely see (flies, mosquitos)
# 那种飞的很讨厌的东西
Those annoyingly buzzing bugs
# 但是能够经常看到蜜蜂
But you can often catch sight of bees
# 这烤肉的签子 和我的胳膊都差不多长
This kebab stick is almost as long as my arm
# 吃完饭
After meal
# 咱们进去看一看
Let us go inside and have a look
# 这些东西是怎么做出来的
How these things are cooked
# 走吧
Let's go
# 在我身后（的屋里）
Right there, the room behind me
# 他们里面是在包这些
Inside the room they are making
# 馕啊 或者说 其它的一些东西吧
Naan, or something else (mainly Baozi)
# 我也不知道具体叫什么东西
I don't know exactly what they are
# 前面（的房间）就是
Inside the room at the front
# 大家在炉子上烤东西
they are roasting food on the stove
# 师傅 这个叫什么
Uncle, what is it called?
# 能听懂吗
Could you understand me?
# 它叫什么名字
What is its name?
# 这个是什么
What is this
# 肉馕
- Meat naan
(repeat) meat naan
# 肉馕 好吃
Meat naan, tasty!
# （缺失）
ehehehe
# 竟然能够听懂我说什么
He gets what I was saying!
# 对呀
- Of course!
# 这边写的是10块钱的烤肉大串
Here reads, 10 yuan for 1 big kebab
# 这个是5块钱的阔埋奇
and this is 5-yuan Kuomaiqi (a kind of naan)
# 5块钱的烤包子
5-yuan Kao Baozi
# 大烤包子就是10块钱一个
10 yuan if you want a larger Baozi
# 每一个师傅好像负责的品类是唯一的
It seems that each of them is working on only one dish
# 比如说 你要做烤肉馕
Like, if one cooks meat naan
# 就一直在这个地方做烤肉馕
one stays here and keeps doing it
# 做烤包子 就一直在这个地方捞包子
If it's Kao Baozi, one simply picks up Baozi here
# 这现在开始做 烤肉大串
Here he starts to cook kebabs
# 现在能够看到的 这个房间里有12个圆柱形炉子
As far as what we can see in this room, there are 12 cylindrical stoves
# 后面这一车的包子
And loads of Baozi on the tray
# 你看
You see
# 他们把烤包子
they bake Baozi
# 都是放在这种圆柱形炉子里
in these cylindrical stoves
# 中间有个炉子是不一样的
There's one stove in the middle with a different shape
# 它里面烤的东西也是不一样的
which has different things inside
# 我们过去看一看
Let's go have a look
# 中间烤的是阔埋奇吗
Are you baking Kuomaiqi here
# 这又是来了一车的包子
Here comes another tray of Baozi, whoa
# 它这边的包子做的特别大
Baozi they make here are of large size
# 一个有手掌这么大
one is as large as my palm
# （能遮住）半边脸
(it can cover) half of my face
# 他们把包子放进炉子里的时候
When they put Baozi into the stove
# 都得探下头 看一看
They need to look inside
# 因为坑太大了
because the stove is too big
# 它这边的烤包子是一炉接着一炉嘛
They have several stoves for baking Kao Baozi
# 等一炉的包子好了之后
Once a stove finishes its baking
# 要让炉子降降温
It needs to be cooled down a bit
# 会打一些盐水进去
The staff will splash some salt water in it
# 这样才能更好地下 下一炉的包子
so that the stove can be ready for the next round of baking
# 目前能够看到的就是烤包子
What we can see now is loads of Kao Baozi being picked out
# 一炉一炉地朝外边捞出来
one stove following another
# 看这个师傅 拿出来了刚做好的烤包子
Look at this uncle with newly-baked Kao Baozi
# 他好像是要把烤包子放在这个地方晾一下
Seems that those Baozi need to be cooled down a bit in the open air
# （装箱的）他好像是要把烤包子放在这个地方晾一下
(For packing up)
Seems that those Baozi need to be cooled down a bit in the open air
# （装箱的）
(For packing up)
# 这边是擀面 揉剂
Here they are making doughs and wrappers
# 擀皮 放馅
After rolling the doughs flat, they wrap the mutton in it
# 然后把它包起来
wrap it up
# 每一道工序都有好几个人在忙
Each step is looked after by several staff
# 好了 今天的包子就吃到这儿
Okay. That's all for today's Baozi
# 咱们明天吃什么呢
What are we gonna eat tomorrow?
# 猜一猜吧
Take a guess!
# 关 注 雪 鱼 探 店
Subscribe